This video introduces the upgraded 3D pen virtual model function and its related function updates.
First, you can draw in the area outside the model.
You can directly draw the clothing version in the 3D environment without having to start from the 2D version.
You can not only draw the curve on the model surface, but you can also freely draw in the surrounding 3D environment.
It makes it easier to build complex three-dimensional outlines.
Now let's re-create the outline of the chest according to the reference clothing.
You can directly see how to use the function after upgrading.
First, select the 3D pen virtual model tool.
When you select it, you will see a line of hints appearing next to the light.
You can just click on the model to place it.
Press the P key to create a template outside the model surface.
In this example, I will start from the model surface.
Then extend outward to create a three-dimensional skirt.
Let's start from using the 3D pen.
Draw a curve along the model's body.
Now let's draw the 3D version.
Here I will press the P key.
As shown, this function allows you to copy the model.
Free extension of the line to the 3D environment.
At the same time, a guide point will appear to let you directly check the X, Y, and Z axis.
Easy to determine the position of each expansion point.
Blue represents the Z axis, red represents the X axis, and green represents the Y axis.
Just like drawing on the model, when you are drawing in the 3D area,
You can also press the Ctrl key to draw a curve.
To improve accuracy, when you are drawing in the 3D environment, you can also press the Shift key.
This will be 45 degrees in the 3D window.
This will create 8 guide points.
Your view and mouse cursor will automatically align these guides.
This will allow you to draw more accurately in the 3D environment.
Once you release the Shift key, the guide will disappear.
Next, press the D key to show a curve.
And show the actual distance between the mouse pointer and the model.
Press the D key again to close the function.
When you have completed the drawing in the 3D area,
Click the point where you first drew and the area where you drew.
Click and press the 3D pen to display the tool.
Then select the flat version tool.
A tool will appear next to your cursor.
It will prompt you to select the area to be generated and press the return key.
Select a section of your version and press the return key.
In this way, a flat version will be generated in the 3D window.
You can see it in the 2D window at the same time.
Using the 3D pen virtual model function after upgrading,
You can directly draw in the 3D area outside the model and model.
It allows you to draw faster in the design process
and combine multiple dimensions to create the flat version you want.
It helps you to create the complex design you imagine more easily.
Next, I will introduce to you
other advantages of 3D pen virtual model.
First, you can use the 3D pen virtual model tool
to select the line in the 3D window by pressing the drag and drop button.
Of course, you can also use the shortcut ctrl and a to select all the lines.
The next update is that
in the menu of the 3D line, press the right button.
It will increase the option of display length.
After pressing the cancel option in the blank,
it will not display and only display in the selected state.
If you need to hide it,
you only need to use the same operation to hide the measurement length.
The next update is that the 3D-painted line can be copied to the edge of the grid.
This function allows the 3D pen line to be automatically copied along the virtual model grid path.
In order to improve the accuracy and speed of creation or adjustment of the version,
when using this option,
the line will be aligned with the recent grid edge.
Next, I will introduce to you the function of the 3D pen virtual model.
Now, in addition to being able to 3D-painted multiple sheets at a time,
you can also merge them into one.
First, select multiple closed areas.
Press the return button directly.
You can see that there are multiple sheets that have been sewed in the 2D window.
Delete the sheet.
Now, when I operate again,
you can see that the 3D pen is now 3D.
You can see the tool prompt.
You need to press the Shift and return keys.
At this time, there is only one sheet in the 2D window.
This improvement greatly simplified the work of converting the 3D block into a 2D sheet,
speeding up the process and reducing manual operation.